Henok Wehibe



henokwehibe@googlemail.com



linkedin.com/in/henok-wehibe

Summary

DevOps/Developer with experience automating deployments on Linux.

Working with AWS and Digitalocean.

Ansible for configuration management and deployment.

Some experience with terraform and packer.

Wordpress thems development.

MongoDB, Express.js and Node.js for Open Alprd Server\Client Application.

Experience



DevOps Developer

Micrometre

Feb 2015 - Present (7 years 6 months +)

DevOps Engineer from a Linux background with 5+ years experience.

Setting up devlopment and production environments on AWS and DigitalOcean.

Kubernetes, KVM, VirtualBox, Vagrant and LXD/LXC for creating devlopment and test inviroment.

Load balancing and SSL Termination With HAProxy.

Custom wordpress theme development

Maintenance & troubleshooting

Monitor System Authentication and log files. Languages: Javascript and Shell scripting.

Version Control: Git.

Automation/Build: Docker and Ansible,

Web Server: Apache and Nginx

Databases: MongoDB

Virtualization: Kvm and VirtualBox Platforms: Linux and Android,

Responsible for providing technology services from creating hosting solutions to developing a Number Plate Recognition application.

Created a Continuous Delivery process with Ansible, Docker, Nginx and Lets Encrypt for deploying code on AWS and DigitalOcean.

Migrating outdated customer sites to secure, GDPR compliant and accessible frameworks with Next.js and gatsby.js.

Carrying out audits for performance, Accessibility, Best Practices, Search Engine Optimization and Progressive Web App.

Benchmarking and Load testing HTTP servers with ApacheBench(ab) to establish a best-case scenario for a project before and after any deployment. Designed and Developed ANPR Parking Management webApp with OpenAlpr using Nodejs, Expressjs and Mongodb for capturing and managing car park entry and exit data.

Designed and deployed a development environment which allows colleagues to provide feedback using Private Version Control(Gitea) and (Rocket Chat) team messaging

Construction and configuration of local and cloud Servers with remote administration

Implemented Protection Against Brute Force Attacks with (Fail2Ban) for SSH, Wordpress Gitea etc. Configured Monit, crontab and Git for Monitoring, with alerts, email notifications and event-based actions to restart or to take other responsive actions for logins, authentication, applications, services, and log-files.

Assistant Manager

Comm-Tech 2006 - 2008 (3 years)

Education

South Thames College

Diploma, Information Technology 1993 - 1997

Skills

docker • nodejs • nexjs • GatsbyJS • Linux • Ansible • Docker Products • Lxc • Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery (CI/CD) • Customer Service